Harshit Anand

imharshitanand@gmail.com 7985974227 Indira Nagar Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

Summary

An independent and self-motivated professional with three years of full-time experience in the communication sector. Seeking opportunities in Marketing spheres with the best in the business, with an eye on excellence and pursuit of growth.

Experience

Senior Operations Associate

ShareChat • Bangalore, Karnataka

02/2022 - 10/2022

- Strategized ways and motivated creators to ensure an extremely high activity rate in my managed genre.
- Was at the forefront of solving a wide range of creator issues ranging from creative, and financial to technical problem statements.
- Ideated and executed multiple hashtag campaigns, including the platform's best ever in my genre, which garnered in excess of 800 Million plays.
- Collaborated with creators and helped in improving the quality of their content, duly backed by data.
- Spearheaded an extremely successful project for my team and conceptualized its data metrics and tracked its data in its entirety.
- Successfully hosted digital meet-ups for my creators.

Sports Journalist

SportsCafe • Bangalore, Karnataka

09/2020 - 09/2021

- Conceptualizing content ideas on a regular basis.
- Writing down content ranging from news pieces to fantasy previews, features, and analytical work.
- Proofreading content of the team members on a day-to-day basis.
- Guiding interns of the team and helping them in their growth.

Writing links

Writer/Reporter

Diamond Books • New Delhi, Delhi

08/2018 - 09/2019

- Featured in preview, opinion, analytical, and live videos for Cricket Today's Facebook and YouTube page.
- · Covered Syed Mushtaq Ali trophy matches, IPL games, and an international cricket game (India vs Aus ODI) from ground zero.
- Interviewed cricketers like Yusuf Pathan, Smriti Mandhana, Riyan Parag, Paddy Upton, Rahul Tripathi, and Akshdeep Nath.
- Featured in Cricket Today's cover story twice.
- · Content ideation, research, creation, and editing on daily basis.

Writing profile

Public Relations Consultant (Freelance)

Try to fight foundation • Banaras, Uttar Pradesh

01/2017 - 12/2018

- Helped in getting media coverage to maximize company exposure.
- · Arranged public speaking events and constructed press releases.
- Devising public relations strategies that fit the company profile.
- Develop effective PR plans using appropriate strategies and tactics.
- · Put out marketing strategies to get teachers on board.

Freelance Copywriter

Sportskeeda, CricTracker, SportzWiki

08/2015 - 01/2017

• Brainstorming ideas and penning down features.

Freelance Event professional

· Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

10/2020 - 12/2021

- · Volunteered in Marraiges, receptions, Mehendi, Tilak, and corporate events.
- Have done venue operations in Dance India Dance, and Amul Voice of India.
- · Anchored in college fests.

Skills

Oral and verbal communication, Interpersonal skills, Copy writing, Research, Creativity, Client service management, Media relations, Social media savvy, Microsoft office, Management, Agency Management, Influencer management, Profiency in Big Query, Master tool, Data Tracking, Operations

Education

Bachelor of Journalism and Mass Communication

University of Lucknow, Lucknow • Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

08/2017

• Completed graduation with 71.3% marks.

Intermediate

Ragukul Vidyapeeth • Gonda, Uttar Pradesh

05/2014

· Passed 10+2 with 82% marks in Commerce stream

Matrix

ST. Michaels Convent School • Mankapur, Uttar Pradesh

05/2012

• Passed 10th with 76% marks.

Languages

English, Hindi